Once upon a time, there was a man who died.
The story was interrupted.
Along with his heart, the prince lost his kindness towards other people,
and even his memories of having fought bravely.
Meanwhile, scattered throughout the town,
the shards of the prince's heart sought places to settle,
and found their way into people's hearts which had a void in them.
Among those possessed by the shards
were some who ended up making their own tales go awry.
I really and truly have been able to become Princess Tutu.
Tuck your chin in!
It's no laughing matter!
If you can't even do that, then you'll never get off probation!
Stop it!
Now be reasonable!
Duck simply isn't capable of doing two things at once!
All she has to do is walk with a book on her head!
If it's something so simple she can't do it, she simply can't!
Then she'll never be a prima ballerina!
No, she won't! She couldn't possibly become one!
Stop saying such awful things!
Oh, look how hurt she is!
Come on, smile, huh?
Hey, it's your fault!
No way!
But for someone on probation, Duck sure has been acting weird and goofy smiley all day!
She's always been weird!
I mean more than usual!
Now that you say it!
What?
Did something happen?
No, not really!
Liar!
Not that there was anything, but...
So there was!
Uh, well...
Come on, Duck!
Sit it out!
Um...
Uh...
So yeah, this dream?
It's about this one dream that I had.
See, there's this really strong and handsome prince in it?
But this prince is fighting against an evil raven!
He can steal the raven away if he shatters his own heart!
But when he loses his heart, he also loses his feelings!
And the prince's eyes always look so lonely!
And for this prince...
Is that all?
What?
Hey, I've heard a story like that before!
Story?
It's from the prince and the raven!
Huh?
Here.
This book, right?
The prince was a wholehearted hero who fought the demonic raven!
Well, he was when they were still inside the story!
Um...
What's the name of the guy who wrote the story?
His name?
It's Drosselmeyer!
Don't you know?
No!
I had no idea!
This is no time for silly books and stupid grins!
Two books are too much for you, Duck!
Make sure you can do it by the end of the day!
Good luck!
You've got nothing to lose!
Don't you dare slack off!
Oh!
So this Drosselmeyer person, does he live somewhere in this town?
Huh?
No way!
He died ages ago!
What?
The story ends part of the way through, too!
Oh yeah!
Didn't he like die while he was writing the book or something?
What?
Yes!
He came out of the story I wrote and ended up losing his heart to seal the raven away!
That means the person writing the story died and the characters in the story came out?
Something that strange!
But I guess it isn't as strange as a duck turning into a person!
So that would mean that Senior Muto is actually a prince out of a story!
That must be why he's so handsome then!
Hm?
It's Rue!
I wonder if she knows about this?
Oh!
It's Senior Muto!
So, he's going on a picnic with Rue.
Lucky her.
But you know, when you get right down to it, I'm just a duck.
Maybe I'll practice or something.
Hey!
Have you seen Muto around?
Is something the matter with Senior Muto?
He went out without even telling me about it.
Gee, who cares about that?
He's Rue's boyfriend after all.
What?
So he's with Rue?
Huh?
Where'd they go?
Tell me!
I don't know!
Don't lie to me!
It's the truth!
Oh, I wonder if he knows about Senior Muto.
Say, do you happen to know the story of the prince and the raven?
What about it?
Oh, well, um, nothing really about it.
A tale for children and nothing more.
Hmm, acting so high and mighty, he doesn't even have a clue.
So Senior Muto is a prince from inside a story.
And I'm the only one who knows about it.
It's up to me to protect my prince.
I'm not playing hooky, I'm just taking a break.
I'm allowed to do that.
Besides, if I see Senior Muto and Rue, I can tell them that nasty guy was looking for them.
I wonder if it's okay to tell them, though.
Truth is a shy little thing.
If you approach, it will hide.
Miss Edo?
Truth is a handsome little thing.
If you run away, it will give chase.
Huh?
Having doubts, are you?
Well, uh, I am.
So you see, there's this person and there's another person who's really good friends with that person.
And that person also has another good friend.
But that person's friends aren't exactly friends with one another.
Do you understand what I'm trying to say?
A mighty wind can fan flames and make treetops sway, but flames burn trees to the ground.
So, wind and flames and trees, huh?
Does that mean that they can never get along with each other?
Who's to say?
Huh.
But if the wind was too strong, it would put out the fire and topple all the trees.
So that means...
I don't get it.
Well, thanks anyway, Miss Edo.
Hmm.
If it's a picnic, maybe they're at this park.
Huh?
Hey, there they are.
Miyuto.
What?
I want to hear you say that you love me.
Wow!
What should I do?
Should I go back?
I should go back, Shinrai.
I'm going back now.
Yes, Ru.
I love you.
Really?
I really love you.
I'm feeling thirsty.
Huh?
I think I would like to drink some water.
Get it for me?
Yes.
Huh?
Oh!
He's coming this way.
What do I do?
He might see me!
Man, they really are perfect for each other.
But they didn't look like they were having very much fun out there.
If he said something like that to me.
Like that.
Hello, duck.
You know I love you, don't you?
I really do.
Oh!
Excuse.
Oh, it's in your mute hole.
Hello!
Um, the weather's pretty nice today, huh?
So it may be bright during the day, but I'm sure it'll be dark at night.
Ha!
Stupid me!
What am I stating the obvious for?
I gotta say something funny!
Oh, you know what?
I really love taking walks, and you really love Ru, right?
Oh, man!
What the heck am I saying?
Probably.
Uh, probably?
I guess I don't really understand what love is.
But Ru and Fakir are the only ones who will tell me what to do, so I...
You don't understand love?
Senior Muto?
Uh...
Muto's fine.
Ah! Senior Muto! I mean Muto, your hand!
Does it hurt?
No. So then why the weird face?
Is it really a weird face?
But you're hurt, Muto!
Fakir and Rue don't say things like that.
It's the prince's eyes. The poor prince who lost his heart.
That's why he doesn't know his own feelings, not even about loving or hurting.
Then I'll do my best!
At what?
Oh, that is nothing in particular, but rather I want to work super hard at all sorts of things and write that injury!
It'll get worse if you don't wash it properly.
Thank goodness it's nothing too bad.
Ah! The water that you went and got!
I'm sorry! I'm really sorry! I'll go get some more!
That being said, river water just wouldn't cut it.
Rue deserves good tasting water after all.
Water from these houses wouldn't work either, right?
Where should I get it from?
Oh, am I not in town?
Guess I must have walked too far.
Ah! Muto! I'll just go get the water, so you just stay right here and I'll be right back!
Wait, I mean, where could I find water?
Oh, right there.
Huh?
Oh, that's a restaurant!
Some restaurant water would be perfect, huh?
Maybe.
Open...
Ebine.
I wonder if that's the restaurant's name.
Excuse me!
Yes?
Well, this is a restaurant, right?
Yes! Yes, it is!
Ah!
One moment, please!
Thank you for waiting!
Welcome!
I am the owner and chef here, Ebine.
Um...
How did you find out about this place?
Did a friend tell you?
No.
And did you go out of your way to find it?
No, not at all.
It was a pure chance now, huh?
Oh, yeah!
How very splendid!
I've never had a customer like that before!
Now, please, sit down!
Ma'am, I'm not a customer.
Not a customer?
I came for water.
Just for some water?
I...
That is...
I'm so sorry!
You're hungry, aren't you?
Uh...
Then why not have a nice meal while you're here?
What?
But I don't have any money!
That's fine!
It doesn't matter!
Oh, yes!
I just made some shrimp paté!
The pendant gloved just now!
But does that mean she has one of the shards with her?
Where did Muto go?
I don't know.
Don't ever take him out without telling me.
Muto doesn't belong to you.
Nor to you.
Muto made mention of a feeling.
Uh...
What's that?
Where is Muto?
He went for some water and hasn't come back yet.
By himself?
Who else would he be going with?
This isn't like you at all.
What are you so frantic about?
Wait!
If you're going to look for Muto, then I'm coming with you.
Now!
Please help yourselves to it!
Uh, ma'am, if you could get us some...
Some more?
You're right!
This is hardly enough!
Wait!
That's not it!
I had to check and see whether she has a heart shard or not.
Hm?
It's cold!
So's this!
This!
And this!
Why are they all cold?
There's not much taste to them either.
But they look so good!
Rainbow trout, Meunier!
This one looks warm!
How cold!
And now rabbit cream stew, piping hot dumpling salad, grilled pork shakes!
They're cold!
Why?
Hey!
Don't you think something's strange here?
Like?
Like why all the dishes she brings out are cold, or why she's feeding us for free!
Who knows?
Huh?
I see.
Muto can't even tell in something strange!
Here's to take!
And that concludes course A!
Next up course B!
What?!
Okay!
Listen!
I'm going to the restroom!
Sure!
Alright!
I'd better hurry up and check!
Yes!
That's right!
It's been so long since we had a customer!
They're eating so much!
But I have to have them eat more!
Who will taste better?
You or you?
Grave?
What?
I'm going to the restroom!
Sure!
Alright!
I'd better hurry up and check!
Yes!
That's right!
It's been so long since we had a customer!
They're eating so much!
But I have to have them eat more!
Who will taste better?
You or you?
G-G-Grave?
What should I do?
At this rate I'll be...
I don't care what happens to me!
B-B-B-Muto!
I've got to save him!
I know a story that goes like this!
A brother and sister lost in the forest find a gingerbread house!
Then a kind old woman appears and serves them all sorts of food!
But she was really planning to fatten up the two and eat them afterwards!
Really?
Uh!
It's no good!
Muto doesn't understand!
It's in danger!
We got to get out!
Huh?
What are these?
What are you doing?
Oh, well, I was thinking of going soon.
No, you can't!
I've still got my dishes to cook!
Your dishes?
More must be eaten! Much more!
Eating more for what?
You'll stay till you're done!
Why should I stay when I'm already full?
I see.
Well then, how about you?
You'll eat more, right?
Probably.
Open up!
Please open up!
If you won't eat, you can go home!
Locked!
Oh, Mewtwo!
Come now, it's going awry.
The story's going awry.
Heart shards make their homes
in the homes in people's hearts
and convolute their stories.
It seems the heart that is too pure
is an awfully heavy burden.
Oh, do tell me.
How will you handle this story,
Princess Tootoo?
That little nuisance is gone now.
You just keep eating.
Oh, who could that be?
Who's there?
Meal time has now ended.
Please, my prince, you must rest a while.
My customer!
Give me back my customer!
Please come dance with me, Ms. Ebine.
I am not a dancer.
My job is not to dance.
My job is to cook and have my customers eat my cooking.
What do you hope to gain by forcing him to eat?
I want him to keep eating more and more.
Yes, but why?
What do you mean why?
I want him to eat lots and lots.
I want my dear customer to have his fill.
Because having a fill of every kind of delicious food
is pure happiness.
I found you.
This person's heart is not where you belong.
Let's go back.
I'm not letting him go anywhere!
Stay away!
Ms. Ebine!
What feeling is that shard?
I just want him to enjoy my cooking.
That's what a restaurant is for!
Then, why has your cooking become so bland and cold?
Why would you force your customer to eat such a meal?
Why would you lock him up?
I want you to tell me what it is you're feeling, Ms. Ebine?
What I'm feeling?
Come dance with me, Ms. Ebine.
Yes.
Back then, I felt a little uncertainty, but mostly bliss.
I could have burst with happiness,
a warm atmosphere, happy conversations, delicious food.
What a wonderful restaurant.
A wonderful couple.
I'd set my dish next to his in point, saying,
who will taste better?
You or you?
He'd tease me and point at mine.
You still have a long way to go,
but that was happiness for me.
Who will taste better?
You or you?
That's what those words meant.
But there's no one left to tease me when I ask about it.
I have recipes, but the person who cooked them is no longer here.
I was so lonely.
So I wanted to have my customers stay as long as possible.
I could at least have that.
You're the feeling of loneliness, aren't you?
The feeling of loneliness.
Yes.
But this is not where you belong.
I'm sorry, but I must go.
Wait! Don't go!
Please! I'll be all alone again!
Don't worry.
You won't be left alone, Miss Epine.
Because you have the recipes left by the one you loved.
Right here.
Lots of dishes are waiting, wanting to be made.
A gift left to you by the one who loved you.
The power to turn loneliness into strength.
My dear.
I feel like I can cook warm dishes again.
Warm, just like your heart.
I'll make this a wonderful restaurant again.
Please help me, my dear.
My dear.
My Prince, your feelings belong inside of you.
Your life belongs within your heart.
I'd like to thank you, Princess Tutu.
Oh, Muto.
All right.
Muto, what are you doing here?
Hey!
Well, nothing.
So what happened, Muto?
Princess Tutu.
Don't tell me he knows it's me!
She appeared and touched me.
Princess Tutu?
This is ridiculous.
That's just a story.
Huh?
Tutu is part of the story too?
But I'm a duck!
Though blessed with beauty, cleverness, and strength,
she's still a princess fated never to be with her prince.
When she confesses her love,
she turns into a speck of light and vanishes.
What?
What's part of the story?
What's real?
Tutu is me and I'm a duck, but Tutu is...
Tutu is...
That's right.
Princess Tutu is a tragic princess.
Stories aren't always guaranteed a happily ever after.
I'm a fucker.
You're Heaven?
Wh jej laughter?
Huh?
Oh, you're too, I have to,
That's dumb.
I found universe.
You have to put it out,
The Watch.
You have to do it,
I have to do it.
Uh huh?
You have to make the way of having a man waking America and choosing
a woman being happy with her mother,
Can we ask her?
Oh?
Oh boy.
Sorry Server.
Sir, who's ever todo,
You dream watch.
So you're challenging...
You have to?
You have to...
All I want to do is find the pieces of Mewto's heart and give them back to him.
I'm not thinking about being with him or confessing to him or anything.
I don't know. These emotions I'm feeling...
You'd better not be the one helping him dredge up these weird things.
Maybe it was Princess Tutu from the fairy tale.
The story will become real in this town where reality and stories intermingle.
I am Princess Tutu, just like you.
I am fated never to be with the one whom I love.
All who love stories gather round.
Like we could answer and we'll be gonna do my last topic in this town.
This쉬 at SETTU
I'm telling you, whatever they might argue.